What?!
なに？
ま…また昨日も心臓麻痺の犠牲者が23人?!
There were another 23 victims yesterday, again?!
キラは学生かもしれないという疑いが生じたとたん、
As soon as the possibility of Kira being a student is put forward, the timing of the murders change to indicate that this isn't the case.
それを否定するような殺人が起こった
I guess this means that Kira must have access to police information.
キラは警察の情報を知っているという事か…
僕に捜査状況が洩れたと知った L は…
Now that L knows I'm somehow getting police information, without doubt, he'll use the police as a link to catch me.
警察内部から、僕への糸口をつかもうとするに決まっている
There's a human that's been following you.
ずっとお前をつけている人間がいる…
Looks like I've got a problem.
それは邪魔だな
I'll have to get rid of him as soon as possible, Ryuk.
なるべく早く消してやるよ、リュック
A Shinigami's eyes have the ability to see a person's name and life span, just by looking at them.
死神の目には…
Yagami Light
そいつの名前と寿命が顔の上に見えるんだ
Also, Shinigami have the ability to change the eyes of any human who finds their notebook, into the eyes of a Shinigami.
そして、死神は自分の落としたノートを拾った人間の目を…
死神の目にしてやる事ができる
The price for a Shinigami's eyes is... half of your remaining life span.
目　玉
死神の眼球の値段は…
The price for a Shinigami's eyes is... half of your remaining life span.
その人間の残りの寿命の…半分だ
So, what do you want to do, Light?
さぁ…どうする？ライト
The Chase
Haven't seen Ryuk around lately, huh?
最近、リュークみねぇな
デスノート
下界に日記帳を落としたのってマジだったのか
Was he serious about having dropped his Death Note on Earth?
It must have been picked up by a human before he got to it.
で、先人間に拾われたんだろ
No way! If he did something like that, he'd be forced to watch over them until either the human dies, or the notebook is destroyed.
まさか…
んなことしたら拾った奴の最後がノートの最後…
見届けなきゃいけねぇんだぜ
You're right. There's no way Ryuk could be bothered to do something like that.
だな、そんな面倒くせぇ事リュークがするはずがねぇ
Yeah, but I heard he's got two Death Notes.
デスノート
しかもアイツ…二冊日記帳持てたって話だぞ
Seriously?! Why the hell has he got two?
マジか？何のために二冊が？
I just don't understand the guy.
あいつのやる事はわからん…
僕が死神の目を持つためには…
So, in order for me to acquire the eyes of a Shinigami, I've got to give up half of my remaining life span... right?
寿命の半分を差し出さなければならない
…そうだったな
Yeah, so what do ya wanna do?
ああ、どうする？
Have we got a deal?
取引するか
Ryuk.. that deal is... out of the question.
リューク、
この取引…論外だ
Ryuk.. that deal is... out of the question.
Huh?
あ？
いいかリューク
Listen carefully, Ryuk.
I'm trying to create a new ideal world, free of criminals.
僕は犯罪者のいない理想の新世界をつくる
And I intend to reign as God of that new world for a long time.
そして、そこの世界の神として、長く君臨するんだ
If the deal had involved increasing my life span, I might have considered it.
僕の寿命が延びるんなら考えるが、短くなるんじゃ話にならない
But anything that decreases it isn't even worth discussing.
そんなことリュークだって判ってる筈だろ
I'd have thought that you'd already know that much.
Yeah. Well, I just wanted to tell you that the deal exists.
ああ
ただ、そういう取引もあると言いたかっただけだ
Thought I'd better tell you this sort of thing early on, so I don't have to put up with your complaints later.
こういう話は早くしておかないと後で文句言われても嫌だからな
You thought you'd better tell me this sort of thing "early on"?
こういう話は早くしておかないと？
Isn't it already slightly late?
だったら言うの遅いだろ
そういう話は会ってすぐに言うか、
You should've told me this either as soon as we met, or written it as part of the explanations in the Death Note.
ノートの使い方の説明にでも、書いておくべきじゃないのか？
Err.. I guess you're right.
そう、そうだな…
He doesn't fear me in the slightest, even though I'm a Shinigami.
仮にも死神であるオレを恐れる事も無く、媚びる事もなく、
He doesn't try to suck up to me, and he keeps on relentlessly asking such probing questions of me.
こういう事に関してはがんがん突っ込んでくる
And?
で、
ん？
Is there anything else you should have told me beforehand, Ryuk the Shinigami?
もう前もって言っておくべき事はないんだろうな
死神リューク
No, there's nothing else.
ああ、もうない
Probably...
(…多分)
Oh. That's a shame.
そうか、残念だ
A shame?
残念？
If it was wings instead of eyes, I might have seriously considered it.
目でなく翼だったら、
本気で取引を考えたかもしれない
If it was wings instead of eyes, I might have seriously considered it.
It seems quite fitting for a god to have wings and fly freely across the sky.
翼を持って空を自由に飛ぶなんて…神らしいじゃないか
After all, it's been man's dream since antiquity to be able to fly.
人類が古代からずっと抱いてきた夢でもあるしね
If you grew wings and flew around you'd stand out too much.
翼がはいて空を飛んだら目立つだろう
それだけで警察に捕まりそうだが…
The police would probably be able to catch you purely on that basis.
今のは冗談だリューク
I was joking, Ryuk.
With all the trading of eyes, wings or whatever, I'd probably end up becoming a real Shinigami.
しかし、そうやって目だの翼だの取引していくうちに
いつの間にか本当の死神にされてしまう
Although, I guess that could be quite an interesting concept too.
そういう話も面白いじゃないか
Relax.
安心しろ、そんな事しなくてもライト、
Even without doing anything like that, you're already a worthy Shinigami, Light.
お前はもう…立派な死神だ
Right now, the World of Shinigami is rotting.
今の死神界は腐ってるからな
They live a vague and pointless existence, only taking human lives because they, themselves, are afraid to die.
ただ死にたくないという理由だけで
人の寿命をいただき、漠然と生きている奴らばっかりだ
They no longer understand why they even exist.
何のために存在してるのかすら、もう誰にもわからない
There's probably no meaning in their existence at all.
多分…存在してる意味なんて無いんだろ
Compared to them, Light, you're more of a Shinigami than they'll ever be.
そんな死神よりライト、
お前の方がよっぽと死神らしい
Well, by the sound of things, I'm doing a lot more work than them, but I wouldn't want to be compared to them.
まぁ話は聞いてると、僕の方がよっぽと働いているみたいだけど
死神と一緒にされたくないね
As a human, I'm using the Death Note to help humanity.
僕は人間として、人間のためにデスノートを使っているんだ
But it isn't like the World of Shinigami is of little importance to the human world.
まぁしかし、人間にとっては、
死神界は決して無意味な存在じゃない
Huh? What do you mean?
ん？どういうことだ？
It's the truth. Ryuk, even if Shinigami like you come down just once every hundred — no, thousand — years, the human world will change dramatically.
だってそうだろ？
リュークのような死神が百年…いや、
千年に一度でも降りてきただけで、
人間界は大きく変わるんだ
The existence of the World of Shinigami is extremely significant.
恐ろしく意味ある存在だよ、死神界は
R-really?
そ、そうか…？
If the World of Shinigami is really as rotten as you say it is, Ryuk, why don't you try changing things when you get back?
今の死神界がそこまで腐ってると言うのなら、
リュークが帰った時、
If the World of Shinigami is really as rotten as you say it is, Ryuk, why don't you try changing things when you get back?
人間界に来た事を生かして、変えてみたらどうだ？
Light, you're turning out to be quite the positive thinker..
ライト、お前って本当は物凄くプラス思考な人間なのかもしれないな
Of course.
当たり前じゃないか
You've got to be a positive thinker to think of using the Death Note to personally right the world.
前向きじゃなきゃ、デスノートを使って、
自ら世界を良くしようなんて、思わないよ
That's it!
そうか…
I've got it.
わかった
What's up? What do you "get"?
どうした、何がわかった？
I've figured out how to obtain the name of my stalker.
今日僕を尾行してた奴の…名前を知る方法だよ
What're you going to do?
どうする気だ？
デスノートの使い方を利用するんだ
I'll be using the rules of the Death Note to my advantage.
"Should a cause of death be specified, a further 6 minutes and 40 seconds are granted to write any further details".
「死因を書くと、さらに6分40秒、
詳しい死の状況を記載する時間が与えられる」
まず、この『死の詳しい状況』がどの範囲まで自由にできるのか…
First, I'll need to test just how free I am to specify the details of the death.
試させてもらう
The next day
Yeah, it's me.
ああ、私だ
Another six prisoners?
また刑務所内の犯罪者が6人…
Due to heart attacks?
心臓麻痺か？キラだな
It's got to be Kira.
What?!
何？三人が死の直前に今までいない行動？
Three of them exhibited a pattern of behavior before death that we've never seen before?
What do you mean?
どういう事だ？
ただの心臓麻痺じゃないのか？
You mean it wasn't just a normal heart attack?
いえ、死因は心臓麻痺なんですが…
No. The cause of death was definitely a heart attack.
But directly before it happened, one of them cut his own finger and drew a strange picture on the wall.
一人は死の直前、刑務所の壁に自分の指を切った血で、
奇妙な絵を描いています
もう一人は、遺書とも何とも言えない文書を残しています
Another left an unexplainable note.
The third managed to escape and seems to have made the effort to run all the way to the staff toilets before...
たって
三人目に達ては、
脱走してわざわざ職員用のトイレの中で…
What is it, Watari?
どうしたワタリ？
A few heart attack victims that acted slightly different from the usual have just been discovered.
先程、今までと少し違う心臓麻痺の被害者が出ました
Different from the usual?
今までと違う…
I'm sending you the images of the text and picture they left.
現場に残された絵と文書の画像を送ります
Please do.
頼む
This reads as though he's afraid of Kira...
キラに怯えた文書…
It could conceivably be merely the actions of a criminal, but if Kira can control the time of death...
ただ単に犯罪者が取った行動とも取れるが…
キラは死の時間を操れる
What if Kira can also control the movements leading up to death?
もしも死の直前の行動も操れる？としたら…
In which case...
Chief, regarding the most recent victims, I'd like to request that no details regarding their deaths are released other than that they died of heart attacks.
局長
今回の犠牲者の件ですが、
Chief, regarding the most recent victims, I'd like to request that no details regarding their deaths are released other than that they died of heart attacks.
報道関係には心臓麻痺以上の事は発表しないで下さい
キラが犯罪者によって何かのテストをしている可能性があります、
It's possible that Kira may be using these criminals to conduct some kind of test.
And if that is the case, we shouldn't give them any easy answers.
だとすると…わざわざ答えを教えてやる事になりますので
I see..
なるほど、わ、わかった…
Understood.
Performing tests on criminals?
犯罪者を使ってテスト!?
酷いな…
Cruel...
It seems as though they enjoy playing games with people's lives...
人の命をまるでゲームを楽しむかのように…絶対に許せん！
I won't forgive this!
If Kira's really experimenting on criminals... what's their objective?
キラが犯罪者で実験をしているとしたら…
何が狙いだ？
If Kira's really experimenting on criminals... what's their objective?
Take a look at this, Ryuk.
見ろよリューク
The results of yesterday's six tests have already been entered into dad's computer.
父さんのパソコンには、
もう昨日の六人のテスト結果が打ち込まれている
The Death Note is even more useful than I thought.
思った通りの結果だ
使えるよ、デスノートは
What d'ya mean?
どういう意味だ？
Having escaped, one of them ran to a toilet that I'd specified in the notebook.
一人は脱走してから、ノートに指定したトイレに行き
もう一人は、僕がノートに書いた絵と同じ絵を壁に書き
Another drew the exact picture that I'd drawn in the notebook.
And another wrote the same sentences that I wrote in the notebook.
もう一人は、僕がノートに書いた文書と同じ文書を残した
Those three did exactly what I intended them to do.
この三人は、僕の思い通りになったわけだ
For the remaining three, I purposely wrote circumstances that would be impossible.
他の三人は、わざとかなり無理な死の状況を書いてみたんだ
ん？
First, I wrote that the victim would die in an hour's time in front of the Eiffel Tower.
まず、「一時間後にフランスのエッフェル塔の前で死ぬ」
It's physically impossible for a prisoner in Japan to reach France in just an hour.
日本の刑務所にいた人間が、一時間後にフランスなんて、
物理的に不可能だ
As a result, this doesn't actually happen, and the victim simply dies of a heart attack.
だからこれは実現せず、ただの心臓麻痺
Next, I wrote "Draws an exact picture of L's face on the wall" in the Death Note,
次は、「刑務所の壁に
L そっくりの似顔絵を書く」とデスノートに書いたが、
but it's impossible to draw somebody you don't know.
知らない人間の顔は描けない
I see...
なるほど…
Lastly, I specified that the final victim should write, "I know that L is suspicious of the police force".
そして最後の一人には
「俺は L が日本警察を疑っている事を知っている」
そう書け残すように指示した
I thought that this one might work, but it didn't happen.
これはもしかしたらいけるかと思ったが…実行されなかった
In other words..
つまり、本人の知らない情報や、考えもしない、
If someone doesn't know a piece of information, they can't think of it, and so it'd be unnatural for that person to write it down, meaning they won't be able to do so.
その人間が書くには不自然過ぎる事は書けないって事だ
Even the Death Note cannot accomplish the impossible.
要するに、いくらデスノートでも、あり得ない事はできない
But, if it's within the realistic limits of what they can do, I can control them as much as I like before they die.
しかし、その人間がやってもおかしくない範囲の行動なら…
いくらでも動かしてから死なせる事ができる
I've got that much, but what are ya trying to achieve, Light?
それがわかったが…
で、何が狙いなんだ、ライト？
L and the police will never be able to guess my true objectives.
L も警察も、僕の真意には絶対に気付けない
The famous detective will be too busy investigating the mystery of those pictures and messages...
名探偵は当分…犯罪者の残した絵や文書を謎解きに
夢中でいるに違いない
Those completely meaningless "dying messages".
全く意味がない…ダイングメッセージのだ
If Kira is really using criminals as test subjects, it must be because they're about to begin something else...
キラが犯罪者を使って何らかのテストをしたとするなら…
何かを始めるのために…
If they make a move now, there's the possibility that their suspicious actions will be picked up by the FBI...
今動き出せば、
不審な行動を取る人物が FBI の目に留まる可能性も…
If they make a move now, there's the possibility that their suspicious actions will be picked up by the FBI...
But... If there's another reason they're doing this, other than to run tests...
ただ…もしテスト以外の目的があったとしたら…
There might be a message in the drawings and text.
この文書や絵を…何かのメッセージ
This is it.
これか…
（ L 、知っているか）
The upper line reads "L, did you know?"
Alright, it's finally time for the real deal.
じゃあいよいよ本番だ
Real deal?
本番？
I'll use this drug addict.
昨日ニュースでやっていた、
Yesterday, he attempted to rob a bank, but failed to take any money, and escaped by shooting employees and members of the public.
銀行を襲ったが金を奪えず、一般人を襲って逃げた麻薬常習犯
こいつを使う
It's slightly last minute, but I'm sure it'll be fine.
当日だけどなんとかなるだろう
I'll try asking a few people.
何人が当ってみよう
"Try asking a few people"?
何人か…当る？
Yeah. Despite my appearance, I'm actually quite popular with the ladies, Ryuk.
ああ、こう見えても僕はけっこうモテるんだよ、リューク
..Hello?
もしもし？
Light?! Good morning.
え、月？お…おはよう
He's still following me...
尾行はついているな…
Perfect.
それでいい
If he wasn't, what I'm about to do would be pointless.
尾行がいないと、これからやる事の意味が無くなってしまう…
Light!
月
A date, huh?
デートか
Yeah.
ああ
However you look at it, it's just a normal date.
どう見ても思いっ切りデートさ
Even the guy that's following me can see that.
僕を尾行している奴から見てもね…
ただのデートじゃないだろ？
But it isn't just a "normal" date, is it?
You mentioned something about knowing how to figure out your stalker's name.
尾行者の名前を知る方法がわかったと言ってたが…
What the hell do you plan on doing?
一体何をするつもりなんだ？
Huh, Ryuk? Didn't you see what I wrote in the Death Note?
あれリューク
僕がデスノートに何を書いたか、見ていなかったのか？
No. Otherwise it'd be boring.
ああ、それ見じゃと詰まらないからな
In that case, just be patient and watch.
だったらどうなるかおとなしく見てろよ
Sorry. Have you been waiting long?
ごめん、待たせちゃったかな
No. Not at all!
ううん、全然
More importantly, I haven't been to Space Land since Junior High!
それよりスペースランドなんて、中学の時以来、楽しみ
I'm so excited!
しかも今日はライトと二人きりだし
And we get to spend the entire day together, just the two of us!
ああ…うん
If he goes out on a weekday, he either goes to school or cram school.
平日は…外出といったら、学校と予備校に行くくらい
On the odd day off, he goes on a date.
たまの休みにデートか…
Seems pretty normal. An earnest final year exam student.
いたって普通…
いや、真面目な受験生だ
Police Chief Yagami's son, Light - no need for suspicion.
夜神局長の息子、月、疑う余地無し
I'll just check his movements today, and then that'll be the end of it.
とりあえず、今日一日の行動を観て、終りだ
But Light, didn't you say that we weren't going to go out until the exams are over?
でも月、受験終わるまでは遊ばないとか言ってなかった？
I guess it's okay, since I placed first in the national mock exams.
ああそれは、全国模試一位の立場だがな
Eww, no need to be so smug.
うぇ、感じ悪
He's here!
来た！奴だ
It's him!
Seven passengers, excluding him... in that case, everything should proceed smoothly.
乗客は奴を除いて7人
これなら全て…うまく行く！
えっ？
I'm taking over this bus!
このバスはオレが乗っ取った！
バ、バスジャック!?こんな時に…
A bus hi-jack?! At a time like this?
Keep it down! I'll kill anyone who dares to move.
騒ぐんじゃねぇ！
少しでも動いた奴はぶっ殺すぞ！
Oi, driver! D'ya know the phone number of the Space Land offices?
運転手、スペースランドの事務所の電話番号は…
知ってるな！掛けろ！
Call 'em!
Yes.
はい
This is driver Sasaki, of bus number 124.
1745車のドライバー佐々木です
Tell 'em what's going on.
今の状況を教えてやれ
ち…銃を持った男に、バスを…ジャックされました！
I-I've been hi-hacked by a man with a gun.
Give it 'ere.
貸せ！
You heard what's going on? Now, listen up!
ということだ、よく聞け！
I want a woman in a car to bring yesterday's takings to the bus stop two stops away from Space Land before this bus gets there.
昨日の売り上げをスペースランド二つ手前のバス停まで、
女が一人で車で持ってこい
バスが着く前にだ！
If you call the police, or try anything funny, I'll kill every single person on this bus!
下手な小細工したり、警察に知らせたりしたら、
乗客を一人ずつぶっ殺す！
Yuri-chan, don't worry; it's okay.
I'll find an opportunity to disarm him.
My father's a police officer and I've
learnt how to counter-attack such a scenario.
He looks small and relatively weak.
I'm stronger than him.
Yuri-chan, don't worry; it's okay. I'll find an opportunity to disarm him.
ユリちゃん、安心して
犯人の隙を見て僕が、ピストルを持った手を押さえる
危険だ、やめろ
You can't, it's too dangerous. Don't do it.
その時は、私がやる
If it comes to that, I'll do it.
It's okay, you don't need to communicate in writing.
大丈夫だ、筆談などしなくても、
小声なら、走行音でここの会話は、犯人には聞こえない
The noise of the bus is enough to cover up hushed conversations from the culprit.
あの犯人と共犯者でないという…証拠ありますか
Do you have any proof that you're not an accomplice to this crime?
A-an accomplice?
きょ…共犯!?
It's a fairly common practice.
よくあるケースだよ
The culprit fools us into thinking he's alone, but secretly plants an accomplice at the back, just in case anything goes wrong.
犯人は一人と思わせておいて
いざという時の為に、
あらかじめ後方からの見張りを置いておく
What's the matter?
どうしました？
No, no way, it can't be...
やだ、まさか本当に…
I-I don't have a choice...
し、仕方がない…
There's no way Yagami Light is Kira.
夜神ライトは、キラであるわけがない
If he was, then he'd be able to kill the culprit with a heart attack.
キラなら、犯人を心臓麻痺で殺せるんだ
Here's my proof. Take a look.
これが証拠だ、見てくれ
FBI!?
FBI!
So that's who L's been using to investigate the Japanese police!
そうか… L は FBI を使って、日本警察関係者を調べさせていたのか
His name is Ray Penber.
名前は…レイ．ペンバー
信用します
I'll trust you, and for the time being I won't question what an FBI agent is doing here.
今はあえて、
なぜ FBI の捜査官が、ここに乗り合わせたのかは聞きません
銃は…
Do you have a gun?
I do.
持っている
So if it comes to that, I'll be relying on you, okay?
では、いざという時は、お任せしていいですね
Okay.
ああ…
Shut the hell up! Do ya wanna die?!
静かにしろ！ぶっ殺されたいのか！
That man! He was on the Japanese news two days ago...
あの男…二日前に、日本でニュースになっていた男だ
静かにしろって言ってんだろ、言うこと聞け
He robbed a bank, killed three people, and then fled.
銀行を襲い、一般人三人を殺して逃げた麻薬常習犯
He's extremely dangerous.
極めて危険だ…
It's fine. He'll never shoot us with that gun.
大丈夫、奴の銃は、絶対に僕達を撃たない
あ…
おいお前！お前動くな！
Hey! Hey, you! Don't move!
What's on that bit of paper?
何だその紙は？てめぇ…
Why you--! You passing notes around to try plotting against me?
乗客同士メモで相談してやがたのか！
Shit! If he finds that note from before... he'll realize that we're waiting for an opportunity to overpower him!
まずい！さっきのメモを見られたら
彼が隙を見て、奴に飛びかかろうとしていた事が…
Huh? Just arrangements for a date.
けっ、デートの約束かよ！
What a load of crap!
くだらねぇ！
I did it!
やった…
Who the hell are you?!?
何だてめぇは！…そこの一番後ろの奴
You! The guy right at the back!
な…何ふざけてやがる
Don't mess with me!
い…いつからそこにいた！
Since when have you been there?
あ？オレのことか？
Huh? You talking to me?
You can see me?
おまえ、オレの姿が見えるのか？
Don't move! I-I'll shoot you, you freak!
う…動くがねぇ！
う…撃つぞバケモノー！
Don't move! I-I'll shoot you, you freak!
This isn't good.. he's hallucinating!
まずい！幻覚を見ている
Everyone, get down!
みんな伏せろ！
Oh, I get it now.
あ、そうか
That note with the arrangements for the date was written on paper from the Death Note.
さっきライトの落としたデートの約束メモ、
デスノートを切って書いたものだったわけが…
And he made this guy touch it, so this guy's the only one who's able to see me.
そして、こいつにメモを触らせて、こいつにだけオレの姿を見せる
Pretty clever.
あったまいい
Don't come any closer!
く…来るな！
Sorry.
悪いな、オレは死神だからそんなものじゃ死なないんだ
You know, I'm a Shinigami, so things like that won't kill me.
"Those who touch the Death Note are able to see me."
「デスノートに触った者にはオレの姿が見える」
"I will always have to follow Light around."
オレは「ライトの後をついていなければならない」
"Shinigami won't die just by being shot."
「死神は銃で撃たれても死なない」
These are all things I've told Light in the past, and this is just the kind of practical application I'd expect from him.
みんなオレがライトに言った事だ
さすが全国表通模試一位、応用力がある
And he's managed to use this hi-jacking to get the name of the guy that's been following him.
そして、このバスジャックを利用して、
尾行してた奴の名前もなんなくゲットか…
Stop the bus!
車を止めて…ドア開けろ
Exactly 11:45.
ジャスト11時45分、全て予定通り…
Everything went according to plan.
Oosoreda Kiichirou... death by accident.
恐田奇一郎、事故死
Boards the 11:31-bus to Space Land from the bus station at the east entrance to the park, with a gun.
公園東口バス停より、午前11時31分発、
スペースランド行きのバスに、銃を持って乗り込み
この世の物とは思えぬ幻影を見て、
Appears to have some out-of-this-world type of hallucination and empties his gun towards it. Disembarks from the bus.
それに向かって全弾を発砲し、バスから逃走…
Immediately afterwards; same day; 11:45 - dies in an accident.
その直後、同日11時45分…事故に遭え死亡
The Death Note never fails.
デスノートに狂いなし
It's your turn next... Ray Penber.
次はあなたの番だ…レイ．ペンバー
To be continued
思った通りだ…彼はまったく僕を疑ってない
残りの捜査官たちも全員心臓麻痺…
さよなら…レイ．ペンバー